In war, the most powerful weapon is seduction.
The Quiet American is a romance, thriller, drama film directed by Phillip Noyce.
Cynical British journalist Fowler falls in love with a young
Vietnamese woman but is dismayed when a naïve U.S.
official also begins vying for her attention.
In retaliation, Fowler informs the communists that the
American is selling arms to their enemy.
Thomas Fowler, played by Michael Caine.
Alden Pyle, played by Brendan Fraser.
Phuong, played by Đỗ Thị Hải Yến.
Hinh, played by Tzi Ma.
Inspector Vigot, played by Rade Šerbedžija.
Joe Tunney, played by Robert Stanton.
The Quiet American is a 2002 political drama film directed by Phillip Noyce,
and stars Michael Caine, Brendan Fraser, and Do Thi Hai Yen.
The screenplay by Christopher Hampton and Robert Schenkkan is adapted from Graham
Greene's bestselling 1955 novel of the same name set in Vietnam.
In contrast to the prior 1958 film version, which abandoned Greene's cautionary tale about foreign intervention in favor of anticommunist advocacy of American power, the 2002 film is
faithful to the source novel, illustrating the moral culpability of American agents in arranging terrorist actions aimed at the French colonial government and the Viet Minh.
Going beyond Greene's original work, the film utilizes a montage ending with superimposed
images of American soldiers from the intervening decades of the Vietnam War.
Miramax paid $5.5 million for distribution rights in North America and some other territories, but the film was
shelved after test audiences perceived it as unpatriotic in the wake of the September 11 attacks.
The film finally received an Oscar qualification release in November 2002 and went on to
gross US$12.9 million in limited theatrical release in the United States.
The film received positive reviews from critics and Caine was
nominated for the Academy Award for Best Actor.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, journalist, based on
novel or book, love triangle, female lover.
The tone is emotional and intense.